1 out of every 8 Americans is afraid of flying.
Most of them don't have feathers.
Rio is a animation, adventure, comedy film directed by Carlos Saldanha.
Captured by smugglers when he was just a hatchling, a macaw named Blu never learned to fly and
lives a happily domesticated life in Minnesota with his human friend, Linda.
Blu is thought to be the last of his kind, but when word comes that Jewel, a lone
female, lives in Rio de Janeiro, Blu and Linda go to meet her.
Animal smugglers kidnap Blu and Jewel, but the pair soon escape and
begin a perilous adventure back to freedom -- and Linda.
Blu (voice), played by Jesse Eisenberg.
Jewel (voice), played by Anne Hathaway.
Linda (voice), played by Leslie Mann.
Alice / Goose (voice), played by Jane Lynch.
Pedro (voice), played by will.i.am.
Rafael (voice), played by George López.
Rio is a 2011 American animated musical comedy film directed by Carlos Saldanha and
written by Don Rhymer, Joshua Sternin, Jennifer Ventimilia, and Sam Harper.
The title refers to the Brazilian city of Rio de Janeiro, where the film is set.
Produced by Blue Sky Studios and 20th Century Fox Animation, the film features the voices of Anne
Hathaway, Jesse Eisenberg, Jemaine Clement, Leslie Mann, George Lopez, and Jamie Foxx.
It follows Blu, a domesticated male macaw, who is taken back to Rio de
Janeiro to mate with Jewel, a free-spirited female macaw.
Saldanha first developed the story concept in 2006, in
which a penguin is washed up in Rio.
Saldanha learned of the production of the films Happy Feet (2006) and
Surf's Up (2007), and changed the concept to involve macaws.
He pitched his idea to Chris Wedge, and the
project was set up at Blue Sky Studios.
During production, the crew visited Rio de Janeiro and also consulted with an
expert on macaws at the Bronx Zoo to study their movements.
John Powell composed the film’s music score.
Rio debuted on March 22, 2011, in Leblon, Rio de Janeiro, and was
released in the United States on April 15 by 20th Century Fox.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics and
grossed $484 million against a $90 million budget.
It was nominated for Best Original Song for the song
"Real in Rio" at the 84th Academy Awards.
A sequel, Rio 2, was released in 2014.
The film explores themes of rio de janeiro, pet, villain, carnival, parrot.
The tone is lighthearted.